SEÁN KENNELLY

Curriculum Vitae



Portfolio: seankennelly.com



sean.kennelly@hotmail.co.uk



07908719455



Parsonage House, Woodbury, EX5 IEG

PROFICIENCIES

Proficient in HTML, CSS & JavaScript

Comprehensive knowledge of React & Python

Designed, launched and administer four live sites

Excellent problem solver

CORE SKILLS

Confident and personable with clear verbal and written communication

Strong attention to detail

Quick, perceptive and enthusiastic learner

Organised, professional & flexible

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I have been living in Australia for four years, and in 2021 took a career break to retrain as a Web Developer. I studied whilst living in Brisbane and returned to the UK in 2023. I am currently continuing my studies online, and am looking to expand my skillset and for my entry into a career in Web Development. I recently finished a Frontend Developer training program with business solutions agency Kreativstorm.

I'm a proven all-rounder with a broad base of knowledge and applicable abilities. I apply the same level of enthusiasm and responsibility to any role and pride myself on my versatility.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

KREATIVSTORM FULL STACK DEVELOPER COURSE |AN 2024 – FEB 2024

I participated in a four week intensive course run by Kreativstorm. All projects were held to a high standard by the tutor, who rejected work that he felt would not be acceptable in a professional setting.

I was reacquainted with HTML and CSS, which served to reinforce good semantic practice and challenge some bad habits I had picked up.

I was given JavaScript projects which challenged my abilities. Work that was functional but did adhere to best practices was rejected, redone, and refactored until considered to a professional standard.

I encountered real-world experience of working with peers and in groups. Collaborative work gave me insight into different modes of thinking, encouraged me to co-operate with others on tasks, and led to exchanges of work and ideas. It also gave me a first-time experience of working with shared Github repos, including branching, merging and deploying work.

As part of this course I produced three web apps which are included in my portfolio page.

SEPT 2022 – NOW

I am studying Codecademy's Full Stack Developer career path course, and am currently focused on React.

Technical Skills Practiced Through Codecadmy:

- HTML:Advanced
- CSS:Advanced
- JavaScript: Proficient
- React: Beginner

Recent Projects:

- Deploying React APP with Netlify
- Spotify API Manipulation with React
- DOM Manipulation with JavaScript

Certifications:

- Learn HTML
- Learn CSS
- Learn JavaScript

CORE SKILLS CONTINUED

Independent worker with ability to source information

Thorough analytical skills, including application of statistical techniques to interpret and act on data

Strong and developed organisation skills

Consistent output and approach to work

Comfortable taking on new challenges, motivating others with my enthusiasm and ideas

Adaptable

Ability to work to deadlines

PERSONAL & VOLUNTARY

In my spare time I am a freelance live sound engineer. I am also on the board of a small charity called the Dumbutu Link, which raises funds for a village in The Gambia. I make music and have released two albums in the last two years. I am an avid hiker and last year walked 18 miles to raise money for Dartmoor Rescue.

STUDENT AT KENT INSTITUTE SYDNEY SEPT 2021 – SEPT 2022

Full time student on a course that covered many diverse aspects of Web and Software Development, including (but not limited to):

- Coding languages (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, PHP, SQL)
- · Real-world projects including websites, databases and hosting
- Development of UI and UX
- Application of SEO
- Client-based approaches to projects

OTHER EXPERIENCE AND EMPLOYMENT

Between 2019 and 2021 I was working and travelling in Australia and New Zealand. The employment I held there was not career focused, so has not been included above under relevant experience.

I worked an assortment of jobs, choosing to focus on variety and location. In many jobs I quickly proved myself responsive, reliable and conscientious, and was promoted or asked to oversee greater responsibility. Most positions were largely independent, so were unsupervised and requiring self-management and effective timekeeping. I sometimes worked in remote and extreme areas, and relished the opportunity to learn from my environment as much as my role. Extreme weather events (floods, cyclones) and the ever-changing face of the Covid pandemic meant that adaptability and a level head were keys to success.

EDUCATION SUMMARY

Establishment – Kent Institute Sydney

Qualification	Date	Grade
Certificate IV in Information Technology (Web Development)	Sept 2022	Pass

Establishment – Plymouth University

Qualification	Date	Grade
Foundation Degree in Arts	June 2012	Pass

Establishment - City College Plymouth, dBs Live Plymouth

Qualification	Subject	Date	Grade
A2 Level	English Literature	June 2009	В
A2 Level	Media Studies	June 2009	В
BTC Level 3	Music Technology	June 2010	Distinction
BTC Level 2	Music Technology	June 2009	Distinction